# Miguel Pallás Miralles, Data Analyst

TORONTO, ONTARIO, CANADA · miguelpmiralles@gmail.com · +16477620878

#### **PROFILE**

I am a Data Analyst with a background in Localization. I have used data to make informed decisions, extract insights, and add value to my work as a localization specialist.

I am looking forward to joining a team where I can contribute to solving challenges through the use of data-driven methodologies.

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

#### Layout Editor (English and Spanish), Domestika

Jul 2020 — May 2021, Madrid/Valencia (Spain)

- Edited and proofread the content of over 100 courses on a wide array of arts and crafts so that the final layout fits the standards set up by Domestika and the instructors.
- Adapted copy to the voice of the teachers by translating and copy editing (English to Spanish and reverse) content when needed.
- Revised and corrected over 150 courses upon release date on the platform.
- Came up with localization and copy edition strategies to streamline the instructor-producer-editor workflow.
- Produced ready-to-use copy that could be implemented to any course, with the appropriate tweaks and changes.

# Software Localization and Natural Language Understanding (NLU) Specialist, Samsung UK (via Modis)

Jun 2018 — Jun 2020, Alcobendas, Madrid, Spain

- Created training utterances for over 10 Bixby apps and improved existing training before the
  assistant was implemented into compatible Samsung devices in the Spanish (Spain) market
  (December 2018).
- Debugged over 1000 Natural Language Processing failures, ensuring the assistant complies with the user's commands and requests, regardless of the device.
- Collaborated with other language teams on non-language-specific issues, such as investigating potential client API failures, or ambiguous tagging of the Natural Language Understanding training sets.
- Using proprietary technologies, I ran daily regression tests to ensure that the deployed versions of the applications were functioning as expected.
- Reported the performance results to key stakeholders within the team.
- Assisted the Text-to-Speech and Automatic Speech Recognition teams in Part-of-Speech tagging tasks.

### **EDUCATION**

# Juno College of Technology, Data Analysis Bootcamp

Oct 2021 — Dec 2021, Toronto, Ontario, Canada

#### Universidad de Valencia, MA in Creative Translation

Oct 2013 — Sep 2014, Valencia, Spain

#### **DETAILS**

#### LINKS

LinkedIn Profile

Portfolio

#### **SKILLS**

Data Analysis

Microsoft Excel

Tableau

Data Clean-ups

**SQL** 

Python

Time Series Analysis

Agile Methodologies

Version Control

Localization

Linguistics

FB Prophet

#### LANGUAGES

Spanish; Castilian

English

#### **HOBBIES**

Basketball Analytics. Filipino Martial Arts.

## Universidad de Valencia, BS in Psychology

Sep 2005 — Dec 2012, Valencia, Spain

#### **COURSES**

Deep Learning Prerequisites: Linear Regression in Python, Udemy (as taught by Lazy Programmer)

Dec 2021 — Dec 2021

The Complete SQL Bootcamp 2022: Go from Zero to Hero, Udemy (as taught by Jose Portilla)

Jun 2021 — Jun 2021

Probability and Statistics for Business and Data Science, Udemy (as taught by Jose Portilla)

May 2020 — May 2020

Python for Time Series Data Analysis, Udemy (as taught by Jose Portilla)

Jan 2022 — Feb 2022